NUH YURDUSEVEN

Title: "Computer Engineer" nuh_yrdsvn@outlook.com· linkedin profile · nuhyurduseven.github.io

As a career goal, I want to use my academic and work experience gains in data-related fields to provide maximum benefit to the projects of the corporate structure I am in and to take part in important projects. I want to continue my career in positions such as data science specialist, data engineer by combining my IT and academic background with my project development, teamwork, and business management skills. As someone who has adopted the principle of continuous learning, I believe that I can improve myself in data mining and software development as I gain more experience in my business life in the short term. In the long term, I want to work on high-value-added products and develop new ideas and projects in order to reach personal and organizational goals by being productive at work in line with productivity goals.

EXPERIENCE

SEPT 2021 - ...

CONTRIBUTING WRITER, HACKER NOON

As a Writer on technical subjects such as data science, Linux, related data management etc.

JUNE 2019 – JULY 2019

SUMMER INTERN, BIMEL&DEPONET

Main duty was testing, controlling, and taking care of various network or display devices as a network intern and creating network simulations on GNS3 software for learning purposes.

JUNE 2018 - JULY 2018

SUMMER INTERN, TUBITAK UZAY

Main duty was creating a tool that configure Tomcat server web archive's configuration files with big data processing group

EDUCATION

SEPT 2020 -

MSC, OSTIM TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

Institute of Science, Software Engineering

SEPT 2017 - AUG 2021

BACHELOR, ANADOLU UNIVERSITY

Faculty of Open Education, Management information systems, GPA: 2.75/4

SEPT 2016 - JULY 2020

BACHELOR, SAKARYA UNIVERSITY

Faculty of computer & Information science, Computer engineering, GPA: 3.08/4

SKILLS

- Data science
- Data Analytics
- Data engineering

- Database management systems
- AI, ML, DL
- Python, R, SQL

PROJECTS

DATA SCIENCE FLOW CODE (DATA SCIENCE, AI, ML, DL)

This project is a github repository where data science & analysis and artificial intelligence studies are reviewed on some data analysis platform tools.

TIME SERIES PREDICTER (FINANCE, PYTHON, ML, DL)

A github repository of studies on time series prediction

TRANSACTION DB(MSSQL)

The database design based on bank transaction on MSSQL

IMAGE RECOMMENDER SYSTEM (API-IMAGEAI-COSINE SIMILARITY)

An http API designed with flask that detects objects and their numbers in images and suggests similar images.

TABU SMART (ANDROID SPEECH API, JAVA, GAME)

A taboo game that is coded native java and used android speech recognition API

CERTIFICATES & COURSE

Big Data Foundation -Level 1- IBM
Intro to Deep Learning- KAGGLE
Intro to SQL- KAGGLE
Advance Diploma in Data Science with R- ALISON
Introduction to Data Science- ALISON
Certificate of Participation-author – ICAENS 2021
Elements of AI – UNIVERSITY OF HELSINKI & REFAKTOR
CSCON19-Data Mining – IEEE CS
Istatistik & python – UDEMY

PUBLICATIONS

- Makine Öğrenmesi Metotları ile Hepatit-C nin Erken Teşhisi (ICAENS 2021)
- How to Install the KNIME Analytics Data Science software (Hacker Noon)
- How to Create a Cold Storage Crypto wallet with a USB memory stick (Hacker Noon)
- How to Use Multiple GNU/Linux at the same time (*Hacker Noon*)
- Create a system service for Flask-for GNU/Linux (*Dev.to*)
- How to create a static web site using Hugo GitHub Page (*Medium*)